# Greg Simon Ph.D.

gregorygsimon@gmail.com

(805) 746-1668

# **Professional Summary**

Expertise in the practice and theory of state-of-the-art machine learning, modern statistics and mathematics, and quantitative modeling. Demonstrated projects utilizing these skill to drive business value in pricing, revenue forecasting, risk modeling, and product development. Team-centered, goal-oriented, and driven to succeed.

Non-proprietary project portfolio available at: https://gregorygsimon.github.io

### Education

Ph.D. Mathematics, 2016, University of Michigan

M.S. Data Analytics, 2021, Western Governors University

B.A. Mathematics, 2010, University of California, Santa Cruz

• cum laude and highest honors in the major (mathematics)

## Technical Skills

Languages: Python, R, SQL, Spark, Mathematica, Julia (some)

Other: AWS Cloud, Git, Docker, Tableau, Google Apps Script, Shell scripting

Certifications: AWS Certification - Machine Learning Specialty (expires 2023, ID#RX11FD2CEB4E1WKF)

# **Employment Experience**

## Data Scientist - Bayer Crop Science via Signature Consulting [2020 - Present]

- Developed model for high-dimensional correlation / risk modeling via copula theory used to aggregate ML model results for financial simulations in new business models
- Developed discrete-choice customer utility and decision models used for sales forecasting and correcting bias in revenue and risk forecasts
- Team expert in AWS cloud services developed team Glue data catalog, developed Lambda layers with docker to aid in app hosting, constructed data storage back-end for customer-facing app
- Completed additional projects using machine learning models to answer business questions in product pricing, revenue forecasting, and risk management primarily using R and Python

# Course Faculty in Statistics - Western Governors University [2017 - 2020]

- Teaching applied statistics outstanding student evaluations available upon request
- Gathering and analyzing student data using Python for approx. 1500 active students in our course
- Developed machine learning model aligning coursework with positive student outcomes (xgboost)
- Developed dashboard to wrangle data and visualize student progress

#### Graduate Student Instructor [2011-2016], Lecturer [2016-2017] University of Michigan

Primary instructor for calculus series, differential equations and multi-variable calculus.

### **Projects and Workshops**

#### Faculty for image recognition 6-week project with TrainX 7/2019 – 9/2019

- Lead five student-practitioners developing convolutional neural network image recognition model in AWS to predict make and models from images of car from street-facing webcams, in connection with Detroit PD
- Contact: Aubrey Agee, TrainX co-founder, aubrey@trainx.ai

updated: April 29, 2022